Quantum computers have been on my mind a lot lately.
最近我常常想到量子计算机。
A friend has been sending me articles on how quantum computers might help solve some of the biggest challenges we face as humans.
一位朋友一直给我发文章，讲量子计算机可能如何帮助解决我们人类面临的一些最大挑战。
I’ve also had exchanges with two quantum-computing experts.
我还和两位量子计算专家交流过。
One is computer scientist Chris Johnson, who I see as someone who helps keep the field honest.
一位是计算机科学家克里斯·约翰逊，在我看来，他是帮助这个领域保持实事求是的人。
The other is physicist Philip Taylor.
另一位是物理学家菲利普·泰勒。
For decades, quantum computing has been little more than a laboratory curiosity.
几十年来，量子计算不过是实验室里的新奇玩意儿。
Now, big tech companies have invested in quantum computing, as have many smaller ones.
如今，大型科技公司已经投资量子计算，许多规模较小的公司也是如此。
According to Business Weekly, quantum machines could help us “cure cancer, and even take steps to turn climate change in the opposite direction.”
据《商业周刊》报道，量子机器可能帮助我们“治愈癌症，甚至采取措施扭转气候变化的方向”。
This is the sort of hype that annoys Johnson.
这正是让约翰逊恼火的那种炒作。
He worries that researchers are making promises they can’t keep.
他担心研究人员正在作出无法兑现的承诺。
“What’s new,” Johnson wrote, “is that millions of dollars are now potentially available to quantum computing researchers.”
“新情况在于，”约翰逊写道，“量子计算研究人员现在有可能获得数百万美元的资金。”
As quantum computing attracts more attention and funding, researchers may mislead investors, journalists, the public and, worst of all, themselves about their work’s potential.
随着量子计算吸引越来越多的关注和资金，研究人员可能会就自身工作的潜力误导投资者、记者和公众，最糟糕的是，还会误导自己。
If researchers can’t keep their promises, excitement might give way to doubt, disappointment and anger, Johnson warns.
约翰逊警告说，如果研究人员不能兑现承诺，兴奋可能会被怀疑、失望和愤怒所取代。
Lots of other technologies have gone through stages of excitement.
许多其他技术也都经历过备受热捧的阶段。
But something about quantum computing makes it especially prone to hype, Johnson suggests, perhaps because “‘quantum’ stands for something cool you shouldn’t be able to understand.”
但约翰逊表示，量子计算有某种特质，使它特别容易被炒作，这或许是因为“‘量子’代表着某种很酷、你本就理解不了的东西”。
And that brings me back to Taylor, who suggested that I read his book Q for Quantum.
这又把话题带回到泰勒身上，是他建议我读读他的书《Q代表量子》。
After I read the book, Taylor patiently answered my questions about it.
我读完这本书后，泰勒耐心地回答了我关于这本书的问题。
He also answered my questions about PyQuantum, the firm he co-founded in 2016.
他还回答了我关于PyQuantum的问题，这家公司是他2016年与人共同创办的。
Taylor shares Johnson’s concerns about hype, but he says those concerns do not apply to PyQuantum.
泰勒和约翰逊一样担心炒作问题，但他说这些担忧并不适用于PyQuantum。
The company, he says, is closer than any other firm “by a very large margin” to building a “useful” quantum computer, one that “solves an impactful problem that we would not have been able to solve otherwise.”
他说，该公司比其他任何公司都更接近于造出一台“有用的”量子计算机，而且领先的“幅度非常大”；这种计算机能“解决一个影响重大、否则我们无法解决的问题”。
He adds, “People will naturally discount my opinions, but I have spent a lot of time quantitatively comparing what we are doing with what others are doing.”
他还说：“人们自然会对我的观点打折扣，但我花了很多时间，把我们正在做的事和别人正在做的事作了定量比较。”
Could PyQuantum really be leading all the competition “by a very large margin”, as Taylor claims?
PyQuantum真的有可能像泰勒声称的那样，正“以非常大的幅度”领先所有竞争对手吗？
I don’t know.
我不知道。
I’m certainly not going to advise my friend or anyone else to invest in quantum computers.
我当然不会建议我的朋友或其他任何人投资量子计算机。
But I trust Taylor, just as I trust Johnson.
但我信任泰勒，正如我信任约翰逊一样。